Finding Aid for the Livingston Gearhart Collection of Scores, 1930-1996
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Compositions, 1930-2005, I; Folder 1-114
  - Gearhart, Livingston Gigue, pianos (2), 8 hands, percussion Gigue [1938], 1 ms. score (5 p.) + 3 ms. parts; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Fanfare. Alternate title: Prelude. For 2 pianos (8 hands) and percussion. Title from cover of 1st piano part. Note filed with Fanfare from Pamela Gearhart indicates this could be performed as part of a suite. The other works, Fanfare and Prelude, are for similar instrumentations. "For Annette Dieudonnè, Paris, June 1938"--Colophon of score. Holograph score (Ink); Manuscript parts (Ink). Accompanied by 7 p. of ms. sketches (35 cm.); 1 photocopied note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 1, Folder 028)
  - Gearhart, Livingston The goat: (Butt me no butts) [between 1950 and 1970?], 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 32 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: Goat has methods devious. Instrumentation not specified on score. Possibly for 3-part women's choir with piano accompaniment. Caption title. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 1, Folder 029)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Gospel train: based on a Negro spiritual: for three-part men's voices (T.B.B.) 1959, 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm.; Accompaniment for piano, or for piano, 4 hands. Cover title. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 1, Folder 030)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Habañera de Honolulu: score [between 1976 and 1996], 5 ms. scores; 35, 30 x 38-31 x 46 cm. + 3 ms. parts; 32-35 cm.; Alternate title: Caption title on flute part: Habanera de Honolulu: canon 4-in-2. Alternate title: Fanfare. Alternate title: Sicilienne. Instrumentation not specified on score. Suggested instrumentation from captions of parts: for pairs of: flutes and alto flutes, alto and tenor saxophones. Caption title from score. Parts written on double staves. Note from Pamela Gearhart, filed with Sicilienne, indicates this could be performed as part of a suite. The other works include Fanfare and Sicilienne, both of which are for similar suggested instrumentations. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. "Revision 91"--Caption title of incomplete score. "LG Final: 1995"--At bottom of flute part. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by: 2 notes from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf each; 28-38 cm.). (Box 2, Folder 031)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Hommage à A. C. [between 1960 and 1977], 3 ms. scores; 32, 31 x 46 cm. + 6 ms. parts ([1] leaf); 11 x 23 - 21 x 23 cm.; Alternate title: Hommage à Aaron Copland. For flute, clarinet, English horn, bassoon or cello, violin and viola. Caption title from score. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Composed for the 60th birthday of Aaron Copland. Three holograph scores in pencil 1960, 2/77, and undated ms. The 1977 score includes an incomplete keyboard reduction in addition to the full score. Also includes 1 typescript leaf note about the score dated 9/15/80 from Gearhart to James Coover and Carol Bradley, two typescript index cards with notes by Gearhart, and one handwritten note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 032)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Hommage a Suzuki [197-?], 1 ms. score ([15] leaves); 30 x 38 cm.; Alternate title: Caption title on violin 1 part: Suzuki variations. Instrumentation varies by movement. For string orchestra. Title from typescript note from Livingston Gearhart. Based on Twinkle, twinkle, little star as performed in the Suzuki method. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Score markings indicate revisions in 6/87 and 1993. Also includes three typescript leaves (some ms. annotations) of explanatory notes. Holograph (Ink). Accompanied by five additional ms. scores in pencil for revised version of 1993 for Praeludium (photocopy with new bass part added in pencil), Minuet, Air, Scherzo, and Nocturne, for which 5 ms. string parts are also included. Includes handwritten note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 033)
    Contents: Praeludium (Variation I) -- Minuet (Variation II) -- Air (Variation III) -- Scherzo (Variation IV) -- Nocturne (Variation V) -- Marche Quelconque (Variation VI) -- Lullaby of Matsumoto (VII) -- Epilogue (Variation VIII).
  - Gearhart, Livingston I'll never try this again :canon in double-augmentation [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score ([1] leaf); 35 cm.; Alternate title: Canon in double-augmentation. For flute or oboe, violin and viola. Caption title. Complete melody line followed by score setting. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 2, Folder 034)
  - Gearhart, Livingston In memorium M.L.K. In memorium M[artin] L[uther] K[ing, Jr.]: We shall overcome [1968], 1 ms. score (3 p.); 30 cm.; Alternate title: We shall overcome. Arranged for string orchestra.. Cover title. Holograph score (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 2, Folder 035)
  - Gearhart, Livingston A jingle-bell travelogue 1962, 1 score (11 p.); 27 cm.; For S.A.T.B. with piano accompaniment. Cover title. Based on the well-known song by J. Pierpont. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 2, Folder 036)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Kyrie for strings Larghetto [196-], 1 ms. score ([7] p.); 32 cm.; Alternate title: Caption title: Kyrie for strings. For string orchestra. Cover title. "Originally title Larghetto; later changed to Kyrie for strings"--Accompanying note from Pamela Gearhart. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf); 1 newspaper clipping with photocopy of Buffalo Courier Express April 6, 1969 regarding a performance of the piece (1 leaf each); 1 photocopy ms. score (6 p.) dated 1976 of the next-to-last revision of the work with Livingston Gearhart's annotations. (Box 2, Folder 037)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Lament, soprano, oboe, violoncello Lament: canon at the diminished 5 1938, 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 35 cm.; Alternate title: Canon at the diminished 5. Alternate title: First line of text: Alas, alas, no words can tell. For soprano, oboe, and cello. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). "Gargenville January 1938"--Colophon. English words. (Box 2, Folder 038)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Lament, wind quintet Lament [1937], 1 ms. score (5 p.); 32 cm.; For flute, oboe, clarinet, horn, and bassoon. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink). "Gargenville. unrevised version"--At end of score in pencil. Accompanied by 1 note from Livingston Gearhart about the piece (1 leaf; 28 cm.) and 1 additional note with the text "Boulanger clef" in blue ink (1 leaf; 13 cm.). (Box 2, Folder 039)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Lament, wind quintet Lament: woodwind quintet [193-?], 5 ms. parts; 32 cm.; Title from accompanying leaf. Holograph (Pencil). Duration from flute part: 2:15. (Box 2, Folder 040)
  - Gearhart, Livingston The little black train 1971, 1 score (8 p.); 32 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: There's a little black train acomin'. For SA, TB, or SATB chorus with piano accompaniment. Cover title. Duration: ca. 2:15. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 2, Folder 041)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Odd promenade [1975 or 1976], 1 ms. score (8 p.); 35 cm.; For orchestra. Cover title. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil). "Composed for Junior high orch of specific dimensions. Commissioned by Martha Gearhart (13)"--Accompanying index card. Accompanied by additional leaf with composition date from Pamela Gearhart. (Box 2, Folder 042)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Oh, what a Saturday night!: traditional calypso: for two-part voices (S.A. or T.B.) 1971, 1 score (7 p.); 27 cm.; Accompaniment for piano, with optional guitar, maracas, and finger cymbals. Cover title. Duration: 2:20. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 2, Folder 043)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Old incomplete chorals (Sketches) Old incomplete chorals sketches [between 1950 and 1970], 1 folder (6 ms. sketches); 10-32 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text of So they say: Early to bed, an' early to rise. Alternate title: First line of text of Desertion: My wife, Isabelle, having left my bed and board. Alternate title: Poor little Jesus. Alternate title: So they say. Alternate title: Desertion. Title from accompanying leaf. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 2, Folder 044)
    Contents: So they say (?) [complete melody line with words and chord symbols (1 leaf)] -- Poor little Jesus (Po' li'l Jesus) [for chorus and piano adapted from melody in R.E. Kennedy's collection, Mellows, 1925 (1 leaf)] -- Madrigals: Desertion, old style [for TBB and piano (1 leaf)] -- Three untitled fragments (3 leaves).
  - Gearhart, Livingston Overture on Jewish themes [196-], 1 ms. score (26 p.); 34 cm.; For orchestra. Cover title. Holograph (Pencil). Also on cover: "Kabalevsky"; accompanying note (1 leaf) from Pamela Gearhart explains the background of the piece, including the composer's choice of ascribing the work to Kabalevsky. Accompanied by ms. (1 leaf) additional page of music with additions to the harp part. (Box 2, Folder 045)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Overture on Jewish themes: Tzena, tzena, Artza alinu, Havah nagiela 1974, 1 score (31 p.) + 35 parts; 28 cm.; Alternate title: Tzena, tzena, Artza alinu, Havah nagiela. Alternate title: Tzena, tzena. Alternate title: Artza alinu. Alternate title: Havah nagiela. "Arrangement ... for an orchestra with less than complete instrumentation." Duration: ca. 4:40. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 2, Folder 046)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Parade of the cliches 1961, 1 score (32 p.); 31 cm.; For band. Cover title. Duration: ca. 4:15. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 3, Folder 047)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Parade of the cliches 1961, 1 condensed score (11 p.); 19 cm.; For band. Cover title. Duration: ca. 4:15. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 3, Folder 048)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Pieces, violin, piano 4 pieces for vln and piano [between 1976 and 1996?], 1 ms. score ([4] leaves); 31-32 cm.; Alternate title: Four pieces for violin and piano. Alternate title: Pieces for violin and piano. Title from accompanying folder. Holograph (Ink) and (Pencil). (Box 3, Folder 049)
    Contents: Duettino on the theme F-G (For Fritz) -- Duettino on a name (For Pamela) -- Duettino on M(I)-A-G (For Martha) -- Alla siciliana.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Polygamy [195-?], 1 ms. score (6 p.); 32-33 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: Down in Eyeran. For SSA chorus with piano accompaniment and optional prepared piano primo part. Caption title. "From Ippolitov-Ivanov"--Caption from p. 1. "To John Cage"--Dedication from caption of p. 1. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 3 typed index cards (1 leaf each) and 1 handwritten index card (1 leaf) from Livingston Gearhart. (Box 3, Folder 050)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Polygamy (Sketches) Polygamy [195-?], [1] leaf of ms. music; 32 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: Once on a time down in Iran. Alternate title: Harem blues. Alternate title: Hilarity in the harem. Sketch for treble voice. Caption title. Possible alternative titles in caption: Harem blues; Hilarity in the harem. Originally attached to full score of Polygamy for Livingston Gearhart for 3-part women's chorus and piano accompaniment. Other sketches indicate that this is based on the Procession of the Sardar by Ippolitov-Ivanov. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 typescript (1 leaf) of words by Jay Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 051)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Polygamy (Sketches) Baghdad blues for me [195-?], 1 ms. score ([2] leaves); 32 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: Here comes the sheik. Alternate title: Harem blues. Alternate title: Harem scarum. Alternate title: Arabian nights. Alternate title: Persian aversions. Alternate title: Iraqi rock. For three part women's chorus with piano accompaniment. Caption title. Possible alternative titles in caption: Harem blues?; Harem scarum?; Arabian nights?; Persian aversions; Iraqi "Rock." Sketches originally attached to score of Polygamy by Livingston Gearhart. Holograph (Pencil). "Orig: Procession of the Sardar--Ippolitov-Ivanov"--Caption from p. [2] of ms. score. (Box 3, Folder 052)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Polygamy (Sketches) The harem scarem blues [195-?], [1] leaf of ms. music; 32 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: There is a tale told in the East. Sketch for treble voice. Single melody line with interlinear text. Caption title. Holograph (Pencil). "Leo Israel"--Partially erased signature on typescript. Possibly lyricist. Originally attached to full score of Polygamy for Livingston Gearhart for 3-part women's chorus and piano accompaniment. Other sketches indicate that this is based on the Procession of the Sardar by Ippolitov-Ivanov. "From Ippolitov-Ivanov"--Caption from ms. score. Accompanied by 1 typescript (1 leaf) of text with pencil annotations. (Box 3, Folder 053)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Postlude (Sketches) Postlude [between 1940 and 1960], 1 ms. score ([1] leaf); 28 cm.; Possibly for string orchestra. Title from accompanying leaf. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 3, Folder 054)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Praise God from whom all blessings flow: fantasia on Old Hundredth, for mixed voices, S.A.T.B. 1955, 1 score (12 p.); 27 cm.; Anthem. For chorus (SATB) and organ. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press Includes text in phonetic syllables. (Box 3, Folder 055)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Prelude on Foundation Prelude on hymn-tune "Foundation" [197-?], [3] p. of ms. music; 28 cm.; Alternate title: Prelude on "Foundation". For keyboard instrument (piano or organ). Cover title. Holograph (Photocopy). Contains pencil annotations in Livingston Gearhart's hand. (Box 3, Folder 056)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Prelude on Foundation; arranged Prelude on hymn-tune "Foundation" [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score ([1] leaf); 41 cm.; For saxophone quartet. "Saxes, Misc."--Pencil note in caption. Title supplied by cataloger. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 photocopied note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 3, Folder 057)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Preludes, pianos (2), 8 hands Prélude [1937], 2 ms. scores ([4] p. each) + 5 ms. parts; 32-36 cm.; Alternate title: Fanfare. Alternate title: Gigue. For 2 pianos (8 hands). Title from cover of 1st piano part. Note filed with Fanfare from Pamela Gearhart indicates this could be performed as part of a suite. The other works, Fanfare and Prelude, are for 2 pianos (8 hands) with percussion. Holograph score (Ink); Manuscript and holograph parts (Ink). There are slight differences between the two scores. Accompanied by 2 notes from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf each). (Box 3, Folder 058)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Resultant tones (?) [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score ([2] leaves); 28-31 cm.; For 2 unspecified treble instruments. Caption title. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Third stave with resultant tones is taped onto the score. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 3, Folder 059)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Ricercare, oboes (2), English horn Ricercare: 2 ob. + c.a. [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score ([1] leaf); 31 cm.; Alternate title: Air. Alternate title: Bachianas Buffaloras. For 2 oboes and English horn. Caption title. Originally received in a folder with Air (Bachianas Buffaloras) for oboe and English horn. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil); Holograph (Photocopy). Second page of ms. score missing; accompanied by 1 ms. photocopy of score ([2] p.) which includes the second page. Accompanied by index card from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 3, Folder 060)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Sambo (Sketches) Little red riding, or Black Sambo: accumulate [between 1940 and 1960], 1 folder ([6] ms. sketches); 32 cm.; Alternate title: Accumulate. Alternate title: Little red riding hood. Alternate title: Little black sambo. Alternate title: Black sambo. Instrumentation not specified on score. Suggested instrumentation from caption of 4th sketch: 3 trombones, trumpet, bass sax. Other instrumentations from sketches include child's voice, woman's voice, clarinet, and bass clarinet. Caption and uniform titles from accompanying leaf from Pamela Gearhart. Other titles include Orig. Sambo sketches; Little red riding hood (formerly Sambo). Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 typescript ([1] leaf) of monologue to be read by [Bill] Bivens; 1 typescript of story ([6] p). (Box 3, Folder 061)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Shiru (Sketches) Shiru [between 1940 and 1960], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 28 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: Mizmore: Shiru ladonay. Possibly for cantor, chorus, and organ. Caption title. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 3, Folder 062)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Short suite [1966], 1 ms. score (5 p., [5] p.); 32 cm. + 5 ms. parts; 34 cm.; For string orchestra. Cover title from score Parts reproduced from holograph. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph score (Pencil); Holograph parts (Ozalid reproductions). Accompanied by 1 pamphlet about Baird Youth Chamber Players; 6 photocopied newspaper clippings from August 8, 1966, Thursday, August 11, 1996, August 12, 1966, and August 19, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 063)
    Contents: Energico -- Siciliano one -- Siciliano two -- Energico.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Sicilienne [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score ([1] leaf); 35 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 35, 29 x 38 cm.; Alternate title: Caption title from ms. part: Sicilienne: canon 4-in-2. Alternate title: Fanfare. Alternate title: Habañera de Honolulu. Instrumentation not specified on score. Suggested instrumentation from bottom of "Revision 91" part: for pairs of: flutes and alto flutes, alto and tenor saxophones, clarinets and English horns, E♭ and B♭ clarinets, clarinets and alto saxes. Caption title from part. Parts written on double staves. Includes note from Pamela Gearhart indicating this could be performed as part of a suite. The other works include Fanfare and Habañera de Honolulu, both of which are for similar suggested instrumentations. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. "Revision 91"--Caption title of oblong score. "LG 1995 final"--At bottom of part in alternate key. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by: 2 photocopied parts in original key ([2] leaves); 1 photocopied score with extra stave ([1] leaf); 2 notes from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf each). (Box 3, Folder 064)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Silent (Sketches) Silent: may the wds. [between 1940 and 1960], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 28 cm.; Alternate title: May the wds. Alternate title: May the words. Sketch lacks instrumentation. Title from accompanying leaf. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 3, Folder 065)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Siloloquoy [sic] [194-?], [1] leaf of ms. music; 36 cm.; For oboe. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). (Box 3, Folder 066)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Sonatas, oboes (2) (1940) Sonata for 2 oboes [1940], 1 ms. score ([7] p.); 35 cm.; Caption title. Manuscript (Ink). Accompanied by note (1 leaf) outlining the history of the piece. (Box 3, Folder 067)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Sonatas, oboes (2) (1942) Sonata in stilo eclectigo: 4 movements: for 2 oboes or 2 saxophones 1942, 1 ms. score ([6] leaves, 4 p.); 32-33 cm.; Alternate title: Title from accompanying note from Pamela Gearhart: Sonata for 2 oboes. Cover title. Based on Gearhart's Sonata for 2 oboes from 1940. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Ink); Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 photocopy of ms. score with Livingston Gearhart's annotations for saxophone duo; note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 3, Folder 068)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Song of the train [between 1940 and 1960], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 35 cm.; Alternate title: First line of text: Clickety clack, clickety clack, racing down the railroad track. For voice, 2 violins and 2 violoncelli. Caption title. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 3, Folder 069)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Studies on intervals of the scale [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score ([1] leaf); 30 cm.; For two treble instruments with B♭ and A instrument transpositions. Title from inscription in caption. Incomplete; appears to be final page of work of unknown length. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp. Holograph (Photocopy). (Box 3, Folder 070)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Study, pianos (2), 8 hands Study: 2 pianos, 8 hands [between 1976 and 1996], 1 ms. score (1 leaf); 31 x 46 cm. + 2 ms. parts; 31 cm.; Title from accompanying leaf from Pamela Gearhart. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by a note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 3, Folder 071)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Suite from "Retchworth" [between 1950 and 1962], 1 ms. score ([6] leaves); 32 cm.; For two violas. Title from first page. Reproduced from holograph. Holograph (Photocopy). Accompanied by 1 photocopied note from Pamela Gearhart (1 leaf). (Box 3, Folder 072)
    Contents: I kid you not / H.O. Brown -- Petite valse / U.G.H. Puccini -- Three fingers of wry / I.W. Harper -- The Martyr-wagon / O.F.F. Tophead.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified incomplete musical part for piano [between 1940 and 1960?], [2] p. of ms. music; 32 cm.; Sketches in piano format; intended instrumentation unknown. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 4, Folder 073)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified musical part in treble clef [between 1940 and 1960?], [1] leaf of ms. music; 32 cm.; With cues for piano accompaniment.; intended instrumentation unknown. Title supplied by cataloger. Manuscript (Ink). (Box 4, Folder 074)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified musical sketch for orchestra [between 1940 and 1960?], 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 34 cm.; Sketch for orchestra. Title supplied by cataloger. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 4, Folder 075)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified musical sketches [between 1940 and 1960?], 1 folder (4 fascicles).; Sketches in piano format; instrumentation not specified on score. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 4, Folder 076)
    Contents: Fascicle 1. 6 notated pages of ms. sketches, possibly an arrangement for two pianos of an existing work -- Fascicle 2. 4 pages numbered 11-14 of ms. sketches, either an altered version of a solo piano part for a work for piano and accompaniment, or a single piano part for a two-piano arrangement of an existing work -- Fascicle 3. 3 pages numbered 1-3 of ms. sketches for what may be a complete solo piano work or a single piano part for a two-piano arrangement -- Fascicle 4. 6 pages of ms. sketches possibly for a complete work for solo piano.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified musical sketches for bass clef instrument and piano [between 1940 and 1960?], 2 ms. scores; 35 cm.; Sketches possibly for bass clef instrument with piano accompaniment; same melodic line with two different accompaniments. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 4, Folder 077)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified musical sketches for two pianos [19--], 1 folder.; Sketches for 2 pianos. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 4, Folder 078)
    Contents: [Gigue from French suite no. 5, BWV 816 / Johann Sebastian Bach -- Flight of the bumblebee / Rimsky-Korsakov] -- Waitin' for the evenin' mail -- [Untitled sketch -- We three kings].
  - Gearhart, Livingston Unidentified musical sketches in two stave, piano format [between 1940 and 1960?], 1 folder ([8] p. of ms. music); 32-34 cm.; Intended instrumentation unknown. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 4, Folder 079)